# resume

# John Leidegren

john@leidegren.se +46 734 304 638 Stockholm, Sweden

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with a passion for technology. 10 years of professional experience on desktop, server and mobile platforms. A strong sense for technology in general and game development. Team player, driven by ambitious goals and a creative mindset.

I write a lot of code, not because I have to, but because to write code, is to me like a moth to a flame, inseparable. I'm a diverse programmer but value a profound understanding of how things work. Correctness is rather important to me, and I don't do guess work. I want predictable results, and get 'em by relying on **SOLID** principles. I prototype and I test because I make mistakes, but I rather work hard and *fail often to succeed sooner*.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Lead Software Engineer

# **SNOW SOFTWARE**

*June 2012 - current* 

Taking on additional leadership responsibilities and continue to drive development efforts across the company.

# Software Engineer

# **SNOW SOFTWARE**

May 2011 - May 2012

I go where the product takes me, both involved in design and testing. I've written everything from Windows software kernel-mode drivers, to web applications that deal with asynchronous workflows. I've built a public key infrastructure for handling different licensing schemes and setup build/continuous integration environments.

I also develop and maintain a lightweight agent that deals with software and hardware inventory on a multitude of platforms. This agent runs on millions of Windows PCs worldwide.

Software Engineer

# **MIRA NETWORK**

April 2009 - April 2011

\_

# Internship

## **ELECTRONIC ARTS**

September 2008 - January 2009

Identified network bottlenecks by instrumenting and profiling the Frostbite game engine. Presented a solution on how to improve bandwidth utilization by relying on a history of previously transmitted data, while being efficient about memory usage.

#### **EDUCATION**

Alma mater, Computer Science and Engineering

# **CHALMERS UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY**

2004 – 2009

Also, mentor for academic tutoring program that targets historically difficult courses so as to improve student performance by offering regularly scheduled, out-of-class sessions.

## **SKILLS**

- Fluent in C/C++, C# and JavaScript
- Excellent understanding of concurrency and hardware parallelism
- Good with asynchronous computing
- Knowledgeable about distributed computing
- Functional programming (Haskell, lambdas, immutable objects, monads, LINQ)
- Solid understanding of software engineering principles (SOLID, DRY, KISS)<sup>1</sup> and common practices
- Excellent with data structures and analysis of algorithms
- Knowledgeable about security standards AES, SHA, RSA, SRP, TLS/SSL, bcrypt
- Knowledgeable about utilizing CPU/GPU hardware for performance gains
- Networking with TCP/IP and UDP protocols
- Solid understanding of Web technologies (HTML5/CSS3, jQuery, HTTP and RESTful services)
- Many years of experience with the .NET platform, 1.0/2.0/3.0/3.5/4.0/4.5 (XAML/WPF/WCF)
- Experience working with and optimizing Microsoft SQL Server (T-SQL)
- Experience developing user interface flows and mockups based on project requirements
- Knowledgeable with content authoring tools such as Adobe Photoshop, Autodesk 3ds Max, Maya and Blender

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Curious and creative personality
- Comfortable dealing with and learning from mistakes
- Big appetite for learning new things
- Leadership and management functions
- Knowledge of various SDLC methodologies (waterfall, agile, SCRUM, kanban)
- Keen interest into all things game development

# **INTERESTS**

• Computer science

- Games (fiction, art, design)
- Guitars (music)

<sup>1</sup> Pun intended, but I also believe that these principles can have a profound impact on how we create software.